Hilda Mason, Statehood Party 135
People's Archive, MLK Library
Hilda Mason, Statehood Party Collection
1806-1995
People's Archive, MLK Library
135
20 Linear feet
Hilda Mason was a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The bulk of the Hilda Mason Statehood Party Collection dates from the 1970s to the mid-1990s and documents Mason's stalwart commitment to the party. The collection contains committee files (most notably for the Committee on Self-Determination), drafts of the Constitution of the State of "New Columbia," files from DC Statehood Party conventions, and files from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights. Also included are business cards from various DC leaders, correspondence, news clippings, reports, and speeches.
Biographical / Historical
Hilda Howland Mae Mason was born in Altavista, (Lynch Station, Virginia) on June 4, 1916. She attended Virginia Seminary in Lynchburg and St. Paul's College in Lawrenceville. Mason relocated to Washington, DC in 1945. She later enrolled at Miners Teachers College and earned her undergraduate degree in 1952. She was a teacher, counselor and administrator in the DC public school system for 19 years, until she was elected to the Board of Education from Ward 4. She served from 1972-1977, after which she was appointed to complete the term of Julius Hobson, Sr., the at-Large member of the DC City Council. After completing Hobson's term, she won an at-Large seat on her own merit. Mason was a champion of education in DC as chair of the Council's Education, Libraries and Recreation Committee (1981-1997), the Local, Regional and Federal Affairs Committee, the Human Services Committee, and the Judiciary Committee. To date, her tenure on the City Council remains the longest term of service in the city's history. Mason was also a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party, as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The law school library bears her name and the name of her husband, Charles N. Mason, Jr., a graduate of Harvard University and Howard University Law School.
Custodial History
Hilda Mason donated her collection of DC Statehood Party materials to DC Public Library Special Collections in March 1997.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the Hilda Mason Statehood Party Collection dates from the 1970s to the mid-1990s and documents Mason's stalwart commitment to the party. The collection contains committee files (most notably for the Committee on Self-Determination), drafts of the Constitution of the State of "New Columbia", files from DC Statehood Party conventions, and files from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights. Also included are business cards from various DC leaders, correspondence, news clippings, reports, and speeches.
African Americans; Black persons
- Series 1
  - Free DC hat, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District of Columbia Chamber of Commerce 1980 Report to the Membership, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Southern Poverty Law Center VHS, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - COG Annual Meeting badge, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Free the DC Stickers, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Councilmember Hilda Mason badge, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program for 10th Annual Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Breakfast, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Local Vocal Vol. 13 No 4 April 1994 (Box 2A, Folder 1)
  - Support for a Bill to Change the Name of the Washington Redskins to the Washington Shulls, 1993 (Box 2A, Folder 2)
  - Gray Paper Products Inc. Info, 1994 (Box 2A, Folder 3)
  - 1993 Annual Report, 1994 (Box 2A, Folder 4)
  - Peace Action Vol. 32 - No. 4, 1993 (Box 2A, Folder 5)
  - "Jobs justice Peace", 1993 (Box 2A, Folder 6)
  - 1992 Annual Report, 1902-1992 (Box 2A, Folder 7)
  - NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1991-1992 (Box 2A, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum: Explanation of the Enclosed Expense Budget, 1990 (Box 2A, Folder 9)
  - Council of the District of Columbia Owner's Manual, undated (Box 2A, Folder 10)
  - Council of the District of Columbia City Hall Brochure, 1975-1977 (Box 2A, Folder 11)
  - Revision of the Council's "City Hall" Brochure, 1979 (Box 2A, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2A, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2A, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2A, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1995 (Box 2A, Folder 16)
  - Superior Court of the District of Columbia Civil Division: Guinan v Board of Elections and Ethics, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 17)
  - Misc, 1994 (Box 2A, Folder 18)
  - Basement Construction at 2314 Peggy Lane Silver Spring MD - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2A, Folder 19)
  - "A Moral Appeal to Resist Facism" by Jesse L. Jackson, 1985 (Box 2A, Folder 20)
  - Peformance Poet Garth Tate, 1988 (Box 2A, Folder 21)
  - Remarks of Dr. Farley W. Wheelright, 1988 (Box 2A, Folder 22)
  - Phyllis Wheatley Young Women's Chrisitan Association Inc., 1987 (Box 2A, Folder 23)
  - Grandaughter Bio, 1985 (Box 2A, Folder 24)
  - Corporate Sponsors and Supporters, 1988 (Box 2A, Folder 25)
  - Full Moon Revisited, 1988 (Box 2A, Folder 26)
  - The Candlelighters Childhood Cancer Foundation Quarterly Newsletter, 1988 (Box 2A, Folder 27)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Index, 1989 (Box 2A, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2B, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2B, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 2B, Folder 5)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "About Now Article" by Lisa McCormack, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1987 Inaugural Brochure and Swear in Statement, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Proposed Campaign Strategy for Councilwoman Hilda Mason and Hida's Helpers, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics DC Polling Place List 7/13/90 Calender, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hilda Mason Reports, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The National Guard as Political" and "In Kelly's Own Camp Misgivings about Pleas for Federal Help" Articles, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Thank you letter, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "While you were out memos" and Business Cards, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - DC League of Women Voters Education Fund, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Letters, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Explanation of Enclosed Materials for Hilda Mason's Review and Action, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Award Dinner and Event Programs and Invitation 1 of 3, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Award Dinner and Event Programs and Invitation 2 of 3, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Award Dinner and Event Programs and Invitation 3 of 3, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - David Clarke Documents, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Washington D.C Schools, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Event Programs and Invitations, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Event Programs and Thank you correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Event Invitations/Programs/Thank you letters, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cash Management Team Establishment Act, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Education and Libraries, 9 December 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Education and Libraries, 2 December 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Education and Libraries Regular Meeting, 5 October 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Event Invitations/Programs/Thank you Letter, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Education and Libraries Board of Education Budget Hearing, 8 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Education and Libraries Board of Education Budget Hearing, 8 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Education and Libraries Budget Hearing 2/10/93 1 of 2, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Education and Libraries Budget Hearing 2/10/93 2 of 2, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hispanic Voter List, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Primary/Election Matters, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Committee Agendas, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Statehood Convention initiatives/bills/memos/news releases, 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Home Rule/Voting Rights/Statehood Party Articles 1 of 2, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Home Rule/Voting Rights/Statehood Party Articles 1 of 2, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Statehood Bio Skethces/Convention Correspondence/Amendments, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Council owners manual, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tax and Economic Statehood Articles, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Statehood: '91 Statehood Matters/events, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - DC Statehood Press Packet Meeting, Aug. 17 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Statehood Papers, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - DC Statehood Party 1992 Convention Agenda (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "The New Columbia Voice" and voter regisration info, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - D.C Statehood Flag Sticker Bag, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - One-Month Daily Curriculum for D.C Statehood Campaign, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - D.C Statehood Jan. File, 7 February 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Statehood Bill Introduction Protest and Resolution, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Statehood Economi issues/constitutional introduction/anti-statehood article, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Central Committee Meeting, 10 December 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Long Island Statehood Research Questions, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Statehood Party By-Laws and Referendum, 1980-1990 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - On the Road to New Columbia Rob Charles 51, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Budget Hearing Committee on Education & Libraries C/M Mason, 13 February 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Budget Hearing Committee on Education & Libraries C/M Mason, 12 February 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Councilmember Hilda Mason Swearing In, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - D.C School of Law "Graduation 1991" part 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - D.C School of Law "Graduation 1991" part 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Budget Hearing Committee on Education and Libraries C/M Mason 1 of 2, 12 February 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 31st Legislative Meeting, 27 Feb 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Get a New Attitude About Cancer 9/25/91 RT 5:10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Get a New Attitude About Cancer 9/25/91 RT 5:10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Get a New Attitude About Cancer 9/25/91 RT 5:10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Education & Libraries Summit on the State of Education in D.C., 22 April 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Town Meeting Statehood 2/12/82, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 51st State Committee Road, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Comm. On Human Rights Brief, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Statehood Federal Enclave - Definition (Nat'l Cap. Serv. Area), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Campaign '81 Flyers, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Statehood (MW File) 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Statehood (MW File) 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising Lists and Proposals, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Statehood Party Platform, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Statehood Petition Circulatior Lists, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Statehood initiative - 1980 Statehood, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Copies of Initiative, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Statehood Flyers - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Statehood Amendment Copies for Distribution, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Bill 4-4229, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Statehood Emergency Resolution & Bill, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Legislation - Constitution Ballot, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 51st Statehood, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - N.A.C.C, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "Washington Big Four" Article Wash. Post, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - DC Employees in Hilda Mason Campaign, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Election '86 Results, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Compact Commission, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - DC Statehood Compact Commission, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - DC Statehood Compact/Commission Material 1 of 2, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - DC Statehood Compact/Commission Material 2 of 2, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - DC Statehood Summit Task Force and Elections Committee, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Report of the D.C Council Home Rule Transition Commission, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Report of the D.C Council Home Rule Transition Commission, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Statehood Letters to Voters, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Post Initiative #3 Actions, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Statehood - Newspaper Articles, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reference Materials - Articles etc., 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Statehood History 1 of 2, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Statehood History 2 of 2, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 2nd Version Complete, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Statehood Information 1 of 2, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Statehood Information 2 of 2, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Statehood - Speeches/Statements Re, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Statehood Article by Hilda Mason for Board of Trade News, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Initiative: #3 Statehood 1 of 3, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Initiative: #3 Statehood 2 of 3, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Initiative: #3 Statehood 2 of 3, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Statehood Press Release + Press Accounts, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Legislative Aide Applicant Resumes, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Statehood - Petitions Statehood Act, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Statehood Bill - 1776, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Enelopes with Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Letter Written to the Washington Post, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - New Columbia, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - League of Women Voters, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Statehood P.R. Statehood Newspaper Articles, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - General File - Mailing Lists, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Statehood Bill 1 of 2, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Statehood Bill 2 of 2, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - DC Public Schools Average Class Size Data, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Statehood Solidarity Committee, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Statehood Economics Seem financially sound, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Material 1 of 2, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Material 2 of 2, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - June 6 1989- Statehood/Compact Commission (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Statehood Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - U.S House Testimony on H.R.51 by PATSYT Mink, 17 March 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Home Rule Study and Voting Rights Act Info, 1950-1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Statehood Model City Council Records, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Bill 7-154 Constitution for the State of New Columbia Approval Act, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - H.R 51 New Columbia Admission, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Articles: The Future of District of Columbia Home Rule, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Catholic Unversity Law Review, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - New Columbia Approval Act, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hearing Notice: Statehood for the District of Columbia, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Committee on DC House of Representatives Ninety- Eighth Congress, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Constiitution of the State of New Columbia - Address List and Statehood Article, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Chronology of Events in Pursuit of Full Self government for Washington D.C, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - D.C Supreme Court Legislation, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Constitution of the State of New Columbia, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Civil Rights Articles and Statehood Activism, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Statehood Correspondence/agendas/civil rights documents/action plan, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Statehood Summit: New Columbia 51, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Citywide statehood plan of action, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Statehood Mission Team and Steering Committee, 1987-1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - DC Statehood Party 1992 Convention- Agenda (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Testimony to C.O.W Election plan/policy articles/statements, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - DC Council Journal - Excerpts from Elections and Ethics Minutes etc., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Calenders, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Bicennial Celebration of US States Constitution Article and History of 1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - One month daily curriculum for statehood campaign and articles, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - April is Tax Day Protest and Articles, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Statehood Calypso Lyrics, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Gathering ideas for the statehood party conference, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - The New York Times: "Feel the Government's Plantation", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Democrats name list and articles about partisan support, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - 1993 Statehood Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - No justice, no peace, New Columbia Times, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Statehood Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Statehood Presentation, 24 April 1991 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Economic Reports, 1987-1992 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - DC Statehood Party Condems Paris; Demands Democracy Here at Home, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Subcommittee Hearing, 1 April 1987 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Domniation, Democracy, and the District: The Statehood Position, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - H.R 51, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Statehood Lobbying info - House of Reps info etc, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Statehood Party Memos/letters/correspondence/advertisements, 1983-1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Statement of Jeffrey Standen before the Subcomm on Jud and Ed., 1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Statehood Flag and sticker, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Rebuttal to Washington Post Editorial " Tax Dollars to Push Statehood?" in Friday's editorial section, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Chronology of events in the pursuit of full self government for Washington D.C, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Statement of Matthew S. Waston on Behalf of the D.C Statehood Commission, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Financial research assoc. - notes testimony and Compact Commission Correspondence, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hearing on Economic issues raised by statehood for D.C, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Oversight hearing on revised version of the constitution of the State of New Columbia, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Statehood Coalition time strategy for Spring/Summer '87 Statehood Activities, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Report on the Statehood Mission Team Meeting, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Statehood Party Testimony, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Fauntroy Reports and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Opening Statement of Ronald V. Deullums Chairman - Committee on D.C Mark-up of H.R, 30 April 1987 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - DC Voting Rights Amendment Correspondence, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Statehood party member correspondennce, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - League of Women Voters letter about statehood initiative, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - "If You Favor Freedom" Briefing Booklet, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Statehood Bill and Newspaper Articles, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Statement by Hilda Mason before Jud. And Ed. Subcommittee, 16 November 1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Ward Meeting to Organize and Train Lobbying Teams for H.R. 4718, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Statehood for D.C: A Workplan for Accomplishing the Transition Correspondence, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - "Taking Care of Business" Captive Capital: Colonial Life in Modern Washington, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Facts You May Not Know about D.C Statehood, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Outuline Materials/Preparation/Activities of the D.C Statehood/Compact Commission '88 Democratic Party National Convention, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Canadian Public Broadcasting Service, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Summary of Admission to the Union, analysis of the statehood bill, and issues related to statehood, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Opening Statement of Congresswoman Eleanor Holmes Norton Hearing on H.R 2482, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - D.C Plantation: Freedom Soon" New York Times Articles, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Congress and Home rule in the Nation's Capital: District of Columbia Appropriations, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Statement of Matthew S. Watson before Subcomm. On Jud. And Ed., 1992 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - How Will Statehood Affect the Federal Payment that has been regularly made to the District of Columbia, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - One Month Daily Curriculum on D.C Statehood, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - The District of Columbia Voting Rights Amendment, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - State Status Report - December 1983 D.C Voting Rights Amendment (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Press Release on Training workshop for D.C Public School Teachers, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - DC Statehood Party Resolution, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Statehood Economics: Facts and Figures, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Washington Urban League Inc Support, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Statehood Newspaper Articles, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - The Island Agenda, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - History of Congress, 1806 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - The Politics of Staehood in Puerto Rico, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Steering Committee on Statehood for DC, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence on Fauntroy's Civil Rights Act, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - DC Statehood Senator Jesse Jackson's Report to D.C, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Common Cause, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Remarks of Senator Edward M. Kennedy intro of Senate Legislation to Make DC 51st State, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Voting Representation, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - New Columbia, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The District of Columbia Statehood Act, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Self Determination for D.C Voting, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Alaska Statehood, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Questions about Statehood and Constitution, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Statehood: D.C Statehood Newspaper Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Constitution: Passage, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Finance - Conflict of Interest Investigation, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Leadership Candidacy, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Initiative 3 Statehood article, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Statehood Correspondence, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Bill 4-450 "Statehood Convention Procedural Amendments Act of 1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Bill 4-450 "Statehood Procedural Amendments, 13 May 1982 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Take Care of Business" Chapter, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "Statehood for the District of Columbia", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - DC Statehood Party Resolution on Military Spending and National Budget Priorities, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "51st State New Columbia" DC Statehood Day, 24 Jan 1985 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Statehood Revenues and Expenditures, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Senate Bill S. 293, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - New Columbia 51st State: Statehood Reception June 28 1984, 28 June 1984 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - D.C Statehood Support Committee and Petitions, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Constitution and Statehood Legislation, 1958-1985 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Edward M. Kennedy Press Release for Legislation, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Statehood Articles, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Statehood Reference Materials 1 of 2, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Statehood Reference Materials 2 of 2, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Statehood Hatch Act Restrictions CSC Explanation, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Misc Correspondence, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Qualifications of Candidates for Delegates for Statehood Constitutional Convention, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - General Elections, 3 November 1981 (Box 14, Folder 33)